

Deepak Champatiray



IBM BPM Technical Architect, Certified SAFe® Agilist

I'm a self-motivated software engineer whose passion lies in designing functional and beautiful user-experience. With eight years of hand-on experience on IBM BPM/Lombardi platform, I've worked on all facets of software development life-cycle. A insatiable urge towards learning and perfection makes me an asset to any team. The technical and business acumen that I have acquired with over 5 years of client-side experience would prove invaluable to any company.

0
· · · · ·

Skill

IBM BPM / Lombardi

HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript

Java and J2EE

Oracle RDBMS

AngularJS, jQuery, Dojo and Bootstrap

XML, XSL and XPath



Languages

English

Hindi

Odia / Oriya

Contact

deepak@champatiray.com





Professional Experience

2016 - today

Technical Architect - Pune (Major United States Bank)

IBM BPM (7.5, 8.5), Oracle, AngularJS, Bootstrap, REST, Agile-Scrum

- > Design technology and migration roadmap.
- > Design scalable and high-performing applications.
- > Technical and techno-functional mentoring.
- > Respond to client RFPs and COE interaction.

2011 - 2016

Technical Lead - Cleveland, USA (Major United States Bank)

IBM BPM (6.2, 7.5), Oracle, Dojo, jQuery, SOAP, XSL

- Lead application data/code migration from BPM 6.2 to 7.5.Own shared frameworks and toolkits.
- > Participate in code reviews and establish best practices.
- > Organize customer requirement gathering sessions.

2010 - 2011

Senior Developer - London (UK Financial Regulator)

Lombardi (6.2), Oracle, Javascript, XSL/XSL-FO, Webservices

- > Own timely product integration, delivery and deployment.
- > Create POC and conduct technology evaluations.
- > Provide on-site support and coordinate defect resolution.
- > Mentor and train junior developers.

2008 - 2010

Junior Developer - Mumbai (UK Financial Regulator)

Lombardi (6.2), Oracle, Javascript, XSL/XSL-FO, Webservices

- > Create and deliver small application modules.
- > Coordinate with on-site team to collect requirements.
- > Timely defect resolution and delivery.
- > Create knowledge articles, user manuals and release notes.



Awards / Recognition

- > Top Performer of TCS Initial Learning Program.
- > Top Performer Computer Science and Engg, batch 2008.
- > Accomplished State level athlete (Short distance sprint).
- > TCS Technical Excellence award for outstanding product design and development.



Formal Education

2004 - 2008

B.Tech(Computer Science and Engg.) - 8.8 CGPA College of Engineering and Technology, BPUT Odisha

2002 - 2004

10+2 Science - 91%

College of Basic Science and Humanities, OUAT Odisha